hello friends let's analyze incidence
companies talk that's L GFC life has be
a life I see a separation and I see I
see Lombard first three are life
insurance companies doing business in
individual and group incidents while
ICICI Lombard belongs to general
insurance interestingly LSE holds
roughly 70% market share of the total
premiums and rest 30 percent by all
other private companies in life
insurance business
first company is a gypsy life which is
having the market capitalization of 80
6788 curves which is largest among all
the four companies which we are going to
discuss here shear price closed at
rupees four hundred twenty nine point
ninety at the end of April first 52-week
low was at 3:40 and highest was six
hundred forty six point forty price
earning is higher at 64 126 compared to
50 3.28 of Industry P five years revenue
za za growth is thirteen point forty two
percent while profit after tax five-year
CA zero growth is nine point nine
percent revenue growth is 26% and profit
is above fourteen percent compared to
financial and 19 vs. financially rating
as GFC life reported a V and B of forty
five percent value of new business so
Lorenz imagine is at one hundred ninety
five percent above the regulatory
requirement of one hundred and fifty
percent it is a joint venture of HDFC
and Standard Life Aberdeen PLC Standard
Life UK sold two point five percent
stake equivalent to 500 shares worth
rupees two thousand one hundred eighty
six curves recently at rupees 441 so
this is above HDFC life
second company is SVA life which is one
of the leading life insurance companies
since financial year 2010 SBA life has
been the leader in terms of new business
premium generated with a market share of
twenty two point three percent among
private life insurers and six point six
percent in the industry in nine month
financially twenty market capitalization
is at sixty three thousand five hundred
eleven point sixty seven crew share
price closed at the page six hundred
thirty five point ten 52-week low was at
five hundred ninety point forty and I
was at rupees 1030 price earning is
higher at forty seven point zero eight
compared to fifty 3.28 of the industry
PE five years revenue see easier growth
is at point nine percent while Pat is
ten point sixty one percent revenue
growth is seventeen percent and profit
is up by 16 percent if we compare
financial and 19 vs. financial rating as
be any life reported a V and B of twenty
seven percent and solvency margin is to
thirty percent which is again about the
regulatory requirement of 150% it offers
a comprehensive range of life insurance
and pension products at a very
competitive rates it is the lowest cost
life insurers with an operating cost to
the premium ratio of six point one
percent as per nine month financial year
twenty data the third company is IC IC
prudential where market capitalization
is fourteen nine thousand one hundred
ninety three crores sheer price closed
at rupees three hundred forty two point
sixty on a pill first
52-week low was at two hundred twenty
six point and high was at five hundred
thirty three point ninety price earning
is lower at forty two point eighty three
if we compare it with the industry of
fifty 3.28
five years revenue CA zero growth is 0.6
a six percent only while path profit
after taxes negative six point zero four
percent there is a revenue big
of 6% and profit de-growth of 32 percent
compared to financially at 19 versus
financial rating it's a reported vnb is
sixteen point five percent and solvency
margin is two hundred seven percent
the fourth one is ICICI Lombard private
sector known life in shudder ICICI
Lombard has rolled out a Cove in
nineteen production cover under the
group insurance category to help fight
the contagious pandemic ICICI Lombard
general incidence Company Limited was
incorporated to me a two thousand it
it's it's a large cab company having a
market capitalization of fifty thousand
two hundred fifty two corrodes its share
price closed a trapeze eleven hundred
5.75 52-week low budget rupees 805 and
its high water at rupees 1440 price
acting is at forty four point one one
which is higher compared to the industry
of forty 1.42 five years a revenue see
as your growth is at eighteen percent
while path is at 12.30 eight percent
revenue growth is twenty eight percent
and profit is up by 22 percent compared
to financial 19 versus financial year
eighteen for the quarter ended
thirty-five December 19 the company has
reported a stand alone sale of rupees
321 crore which is down fourteen point
zero eight percent from last quarter
sales of three hundred seventy three
point 25 corrode and it's a upside by
fifteen point eighty five percent from
last year same quarter sales of rupees
two hundred seventy six point eighty
three cross country has reported net
profit after tax of rupees two hundred
ninety four point seven corrode in the
latest quarter
so guys let me recapitulate now please
direct your focus on the data majority
of the shear prices has dropped in the
markets to the tune of 30% 50% or even
more if we compared between these four
companies an SDS in life and ICS alone
batted down after 30 percent while SBI
life and ICICI Prudential are down aprox
40% all the four companies sgfc
SBI ICS differential I see long but has
very good reach to the customers due to
their wide represents in all the corners
of India insurance business is still
under penetrated compared to other
countries and also considering the
population of India you can trust this
industry to invest from long term
perspective the parentage of all the
three companies are also very good so my
view is that as DFC life is the first
choice due to higher revenue and profits
refer that table and the second should
be the SBA life insurance business
ICAC Lombard in general incidence
business is to be considered separately
and it's a revenue and profits are
really doing better while buying please
do not refer to the 52-week high just
focus on the 52-week low prices in the
table itself and plan your buying once
you start getting good news of receding
the coronavirus impact also buy and hold
these years for a longer period I will
end this with a coat of Warren Buffett
that if you cannot keep the shears for
minimum ten years then do not buy it
even for a single day thanks and see you
again take care stay healthy and stay
wealthy